Recognizing when a friend or colleague feels sad, angry or surprised is key to getting along with others.
识别出朋友或同事何时感到悲伤、愤怒或惊讶，是与他人和睦相处的关键。
But a new study suggests that being sensitive to people’s feelings may sometimes come with an extra dose of stress.
但一项新研究表明，对他人的情绪敏感，有时可能会带来额外的压力。
This and other research challenge the prevailing view that emotional intelligence is uniformly beneficial to its bearer.
这项研究和其他研究都对“情商对其拥有者一概有益”这一主流观点提出了质疑。
In a study, psychologist Myriam Bechtoldt of the Frankfurt School of Finance and Management in Germany and her colleague asked 166 male university students a series of questions to measure their emotional intelligence.
在一项研究中，德国法兰克福金融管理学院的心理学家米丽亚姆·贝希托尔特和她的一位同事向166名男大学生提出了一系列问题，以测量他们的情商。
For example, they showed the students photographs of people’s faces and asked them to what extent feelings such as happiness or disgust were being expressed.
例如，他们给学生们看人脸照片，并问他们这些面孔在多大程度上流露出快乐或厌恶之类的情绪。
The students then had to give job talks in front of judges who displayed serious facial expressions.
随后，学生们必须在面带严肃表情的评委面前做求职演讲。
The scientists measured concentrations of stress hormones in the students’ saliva before and after the talk.
科学家们在演讲前后测量了学生唾液中压力激素的浓度。
In students who were rated more emotionally intelligent, the stress measures increased more during the experiment and took longer to go back to baseline.
在被评定为情商更高的学生身上，压力指标在实验过程中升得更多，回落到基线水平所需的时间也更长。
The findings suggest that some people may be too emotionally clever for their own good, says Bechtoldt.
贝希托尔特说，研究结果表明，有些人在情绪方面可能过于聪明，反而对自己不利。
“Sometimes you can be so good at something that it causes trouble,” she notes.
“有时候，你可能太擅长某件事，以至于惹出麻烦。”她指出。
Indeed, the study adds to previous research hinting at a dark side of emotional intelligence.
的确，以往已有研究暗示情商存在阴暗的一面，这项研究又为此增添了新的证据。
A study published in 2002 in Personality and Individual Differences suggested that emotionally perceptive people might be particularly influenced by feelings of depression and hopelessness.
2002年发表在《人格与个体差异》上的一项研究表明，善于察觉情绪的人受抑郁和绝望情绪的影响可能尤其大。
Furthermore, several studies have implied that emotional intelligence can be used to manipulate others for personal gain.
此外，已有几项研究暗示，情商可以用来操纵他人，以谋取私利。
More research is needed to see how exactly the relation between emotional intelligence and stress would play out in women and in people of different ages and education levels.
还需要更多研究，才能弄清情商与压力之间的关系在女性以及不同年龄和受教育程度的人身上究竟会如何体现。
Nevertheless, emotional intelligence is a useful skill to have, as long as you learn to also properly cope with emotions—both others’ and your own, says Bechtoldt.
贝希托尔特说，尽管如此，情商仍是一项有用的技能，只要你同时学会妥善应对情绪——既包括他人的情绪，也包括你自己的情绪。
For example, some sensitive individuals may assume responsibility for other people’s sadness or anger, which ultimately stresses them out.
例如，一些敏感的人可能会为别人的悲伤或愤怒承担起责任，而这最终会让他们压力重重。
Remember, as Bechtoldt says, “you are not responsible for how other people feel.”
请记住，正如贝希托尔特所说，“你无须为别人的感受负责。”